- It 's in there . Number nine . - Right .
Don 't stand around . Go on home , all of you .
- What happened , constable ? - Well ...
- ... there 's been another murder . - A murder .
There 's nothing you can do . I told you to go home . Go on .
Oh , just a minute , miss .
Are you alone ?
You work out at the Warren home , don 't you ?
That 's nearly two miles from here .
You 'd better hurry if you 're gonna get there before dark .
- Got any ideas who did it , constable ? - Yeah .
Same fella did the first one . Same fella did the second one .
But who he is , I don 't know .
Somebody in this town . Somebody we all know .
Somebody we see every day . Might be me . Might be you .
Why , how could- - ? I mean ...
- ... I was here at my desk , anyway . - Oh , be quiet .
Didn 't know you was called , Dr. Parry .
I wasn 't . As I was leaving the office , I heard about the murder .
Thought I 'd see if there 's anything I could do .
Well , there ain 't . Unless , of course
you 're good enough to uncork a miracle
and bring the dead back to life .
I don 't think I 'm that good .
There 's no sense in you going up . She 's dead , all right .
Dr. Harvey 's up there , and that 's what he says . She 's dead .
Well , in that event , constable , I certainly can 't do her any harm .
- Hello , Parry . - Dr . Harvey .
There 's nothing for you to do , unless you 're sightseeing .
- How was she killed ? - Strangled .
- She was dead when we got here . - Who was she ?
That lame girl that worked over at Nelson 's .
How awful .
She was just in my office last week .
Did she pay her bill or was this her way of getting out of it ?
I haven 't enough experience to make that sort of joke .
Perhaps not , Dr. Parry .
- I 'll run along . - Oh , just a minute .
I hear you were over to see Mr. Stover last night .
- Yes , I was . - Don 't you know he 's my patient ?
I only went because they called me .
They told me that you 'd refused to go until morning .
- I thought it might be serious . - You 've got a lot to learn , young fella .
You 've only been here a short time . I 've been here for a good many years .
If I answered all the calls as they came , I wouldn 't get any sleep at all .
Well , that 's why I think there 's room for two doctors in this town .
Reckon so , but let the competition be on an open plane . Ethics .
You get what I mean , Parry ?
If ever I 'm called on an emergency , and you 're sleeping
I intend to go .
That 's very noble and ambitious . Don 't let anything discourage you .
Nothing will .
Oh , by the way
you might like to see what the Stovers did
to that prescription you wrote last night .
I 'm gonna make some calls , Helen . I 'll take you to the crossroads .
Were you at the hotel ?
Wasn 't a very nice thing to have happen on your afternoon off .
I 've been pretty busy lately .
I haven 't had much of a chance to drop in and see you .
But I 've been thinking about you a great deal .
You haven 't any family , Helen . No one else to worry about you .
And I got to wondering just how long you were going on like this .
I mean , doing the work you 're doing at the Warrens ' .
You wanted to be a nurse or a teacher .
You mean , you 're going to give up that
without making an effort to get your voice back again ?
Yes , I know , Helen , you did see a doctor once .
That was a long time ago .
They might have discovered a lot since then .
There are specialists in Boston now .
I don 't want to build your hopes up , Helen
but it seems such a shame to give up so easily .
You 'd rather I wouldn 't talk about it , wouldn 't you ?
All right , I won 't .
You know the words to that tune ?
Dr. Parry .
- Hello , Freddy . - Pa 's sick , Dr. Parry , bad .
They didn 't send you for me ?
Ma sent me for Dr. Harvey , but Pa wants you to come .
I 'm afraid I can 't help you out this time , Freddy .
You don 't understand . Your father 's Dr. Harvey 's patient .
We 'll have to try and find him for you . I 'll call him as soon as I get home .
Oh , please , Dr. Parry , you come . I want you to come .
All right , come on , get in . We 'll go up and have a look .
I 'll run you home afterwards .
Afraid you 'll be late ?
Are you sure you 'll be all right ?
You 'll go straight home , won 't you , Helen ?
Oh , it 's you . Thank heavens .
They phoned us about the murder .
For a while I thought it might have been you .
It 's terrible . That 's what it is .
Horrible .
As if it isn 't bad enough murdering people
but all these defenseless women .
First there was the girl with a scar on her face .
Then that poor simple-minded creature
and now this cripple . It seems like ... .
I guess you 've had enough for one afternoon .
Now- - Now , get your wet shoes off before you catch your death .
And you 'd better get up to Mrs. Warren straightaway .
She 's raising a rumpus with that nurse of hers again .
Won 't even allow her in the room now .
She sent down word for you to go up the moment you came in .
Is that someone at the front door ?
Who 's there ?
I don 't understand .
I closed that window when the storm started .
I 'll get a hammer and fix that shutter .
It was him !
Carleton , bad dog !
Out all day and only home in time to get under my feet and break my- -
You 're a no-good loafer , that 's what you are .
Criminals and murderers loose
and you 're out courting the neighbor 's dog .
Oh , Carleton , Carleton , you deserve a good beating .
Guess I better dry you first .
You 'll catch your death of cold , that 's what you will .
And if you think this is all I 've got to do , you 're mistaken .
I think I better fix that window first .
And I hope that Carleton is all that came in .
I won 't need you . You 'd better get up to Mrs. Warren .
Helen ?
Haven 't you gone in to Mrs. Warren yet ?
Hurry along , will you ?
It 's about time . Mrs. Warren 's been asking for you all afternoon .
She won 't let me do anything for her . Oh , no .
I 'm ordered to sit out in the hallway . Why in the world am I kept on here
to nurse someone who can 't stand the sight of me ?
But then , I can 't stand the sight of her either .
I 've nursed some queer ones in my time
but she 's got them all beat . She 's sly too .
Even with her eyes shut , she seems to be watching you like an evil spirit .
But get in there before she gets herself into another tantrum .
I got him before he got me .
The tiger , I mean .
I was as good as any man .
You 're not only late , but you 're playing games .
Why are you so late ?
Never mind . Never mind .
Come here .
I hoped you were never coming back
that you 'd run away .
Leave this house tonight if you know what 's good for you .
You understand ?
Who 's there ?
I told you to sit in the hall . Why must you spy on me ?
I 'm not spying on you . It 's time for your medicine .
- Helen can give me my medicine . - I don 't know what I 'm being paid for .
You 're being paid to sit in the hall . That 's all you 're good for . Get out .
That was the constable at the front door , professor .
He wants to see you .
I 've asked him to wait in the living room .
Thank you .
- Put these in order , will you ? - Yes , sir .
- Oh , constable ? - Yes , Professor Warren ?
I 'll be with you in just a moment .
Blanche , get these ready as quickly as possible .
Yes , sir .
- Hello , constable . - Hello , professor .
- Wouldn 't you like to sit down ? - Oh , no . No , thanks .
You sure got a lot of interesting things here .
- What 's this ? - That ? Plant life .
You mean to say you can write a whole book about ...
- ... little stuff like this ? - Yes .
What did you want to see me about ?
Oh , a couple of things , professor .
I hate to bother you at this time of night
but I figure it 's important enough .
You know , there 's been another murder .
Yes , so I 've heard .
What I want to say is
that we 've traced the murderer to this vicinity .
- Are you certain ? - Yes , that 's why I 've come here .
That 's why I 'm asking everyone to be careful .
Keep your doors and windows locked tonight .
Well , I 'll see that your orders are carried out , constable .
I 'm especially worried about that girl who works for you .
- Helen ? - Yes .
You see , every one of those girls murdered
had something the matter with her . Something wrong .
You mean some sort of an affliction ?
Yes . Now , my hunch is that this murderer , whoever he is , is- -
I understand exactly what you mean , and I assure you
that I shall be especially careful about Helen .
As a matter of fact , I 'll see that somebody is with her at all times .
Good .
Oh , you scared the life out of me , Stephen .
I didn 't hear you come in .
Don 't stop typing .
How many times have I asked you not to see me when I 'm working ?
It 's so embarrassing .
- Please , leave me alone . - I can 't stay away from you .
Now , when am I going to see you , and where ?
You 're not going to see me at all if you don 't let me finish this .
But I 'm so bored . I don 't know what to do with myself .
Stephen , you 're going to get us into trouble . Now , please go .
No .
Then I 'll just have to finish this some place else .
Oh , Miss Blanche .
Yes , Mr. Warren .
Stephen .
You remember my stepbrother ?
I sure do . Haven 't seen you in a long time , Mr. Warren .
Heard you were back . How 'd you leave things over in Europe ?
I left everything in order . They like you to .
- Paris must be quite a town . - Yes , it is .
Lots of beautiful women .
From what I 've seen , they 're not so bad here either .
Always wanted to go there myself
but I 've been married since I was 1 6 .
Never had a chance . Must be pretty exciting .
I understand it 's been pretty exciting here for you too .
- Oh , yes , it has been at that . - Wish there was something I could do .
- Don 't think there is . - Stephen
the constable wants to know if anyone left the house today .
Nothing personal , I assure you .
I 've been asked to check up on everybody .
I haven 't been out all day , constable .
That 's all I wanted to know . Thank you very much .
Good night . Don 't forget to lock your doors .
I won 't .
His stepbrother gave him an accusing look .
Oh , professor , could I see you for a moment , please ?
Would you mind calling him ? He doesn 't know me .
You 're not afraid of him , are you ?
- I 'm sure he loves policemen . - I 'm not in uniform .
All right , Carleton , go away .
- Well , good night . - Good night .
Anything wrong , Albert ? Professor ?
I just stopped by to tell them the same thing I told you in town today , Oates .
- See anything on your way home ? - Nope .
- Well , good night , professor . - Good night .
- Your hat , Oates . - Oh , yeah , keep forgetting .
Come along , Carleton .
Evening , Helen .
Helen , I want to talk to you a moment .
Now , Helen , I don 't want to frighten you
but because of what happened in town
we have to be especially careful for the next few days .
If you should see anything outside of this house , or even in it
that makes you suspicious , I want you to let me know .
See that someone else does your outside work .
You stay in the house .
And don 't hesitate to come to me at any hour if you need help .
Now you may go up to my stepmother , if you wish .
Helen
remember what I told you .
Don 't trust anyone .
Leave the fire alone , Helen .
Pack your things , leave this house tonight .
Too many trees
stretch out their branches
knock the window
try to get in .
When it 's dark , they move . I 've seen them .
Creeping up to the house .
Go away , my dear .
You 're such a little girl .
I want to take care of you .
If you won 't leave the house as l- - I ask you to
you must sleep in this room tonight .
Don 't be afraid of me .
I wanna take care of you .
You see
you 're not safe , my dear .
Oh , leave me alone .
You 're worse than Nurse Barker .
Stop fussing .
If you won 't leave the house as I ask
the least you can do is to leave me alone .
Go over there and sit down .
Sit down .
Stay where you are . I don 't need your help .
Mind your own business .
Helen , what is it ?
Mother must be worse . Get Albert .
Give me the brandy , Helen .
It 's empty . Is there any more ?
Give me the ether , then .
Don 't stand there , give me the ether .
Why did you have to come back , Stephen ?
- Why didn 't you stay in Europe ? - Mother .
There 's always trouble when you come , Stephen .
Always trouble .
Why didn 't you stay away ?
I want Dr. Parry .
- Dr . Parry ? - Yes .
You said you didn 't want him here anymore .
You and Albert decided that .
I want Dr. Parry .
Mother , we 've given him a chance . You haven 't improved any .
I 'll never improve with that ancient Dr. Harvey .
Stupid girl . It 's all your fault .
You brought on this attack .
She deliberately refused to let me have my spectacle case .
Mother , Helen wouldn 't have any reason for refusing to give it to you .
Never mind , never mind . We won 't talk about it anymore .
Get out now , both of you .
Go and call Dr. Parry .
Will you be all right ?
After all these years , you ask me if I 'll be all right .
Oh , Stephen .
Get out . Take that ether with you .
Well , Mother , I can see that you 're feeling better already .
I don 't like that ether . I don 't think it does any good .
But Dr. Parry and Dr. Harvey explained to you
that , taken in small quantities , it 's a stimulant rather than a depressant .
It did help you , didn 't it ?
There 's been another murder , hasn 't there ?
Nobody told me .
Nobody had to .
I always know everything .
Oh , Blanche .
Oh , Blanche , if you don 't come here I 'll come over
Yes , I 'll come over Yes , I 'll come over
Pale hands I loved beside the Shalimar
Now , now .
Oh , Steve , I 'm so unhappy .
Stephen .
- Where were you this afternoon ? - Why ?
- Those are mine . - I know .
So you 've unmasked me .
Well , I don 't know whether I 've unmasked you or not
but I don 't know why you told him you weren 't out when you were .
Well , to be honest , I didn 't want to discuss it in front of anyone .
Well , how stupid of you .
If anyone had seen you , you would have made it awkward for all of us .
Where were you ?
- Professor , l- - - Blanche
would you be good enough to leave us ?
Let 's stop sparring .
You 're angry because I took Blanche out .
You 're angry because since I 've been home
Blanche and I have gotten to know each other pretty well .
You know , Stephen , you always did smirk
even when you were a child .
It 's one of the things my father disliked about you .
He was my father too .
I 'm inclined to think that Father was disappointed in both of us .
Neither of us fitted his concept of what a real man should be :
A gun-toting , hard-drinking , tough-living , God-fearing citizen .
He always used to say :
" The strong survive , the weak die . "
How wrong he was , Albert
because you and I
the meek
have inherited the earth .
I 'll be honest with you , Stephen .
I don 't like you . I never have .
I have never trusted you .
And you 're quite right when you say that I don 't like
this interest you have in Blanche .
And I 'll tell you something else .
I 've had the responsibility of your mother , not mine
for years , and I 'm tired and strained .
Therefore , I think we should make a decision .
Either you make up your mind to go away permanently
or , if you like , you stay and let me go .
Helen
you look as though you lost your best friend .
You got nothing to worry about .
If anybody tried any of their funny business on you
I 'd soon sock them in the jaw .
Look at it this way , Helen .
Murder 's like a million-dollar lottery .
Sure , it is . Listen . You pick up the newspaper .
You see someone 's picture who 's won a million dollars .
You pick up another paper .
There 's a picture of someone who 's been murdered .
But it 's never me and it 's never you .
It 's always somebody else , isn 't it ?
There 's safety in numbers , Helen .
There 's Oates and me and the professor and Stephen .
- We 'll look after you . - And there 's Carleton too .
Shouldn 't count too much on him .
And there 's Nurse Barker . She 'd be as good as any man .
In fact , sometimes I think she is a man .
In case you 're interested
there 's someone at the front door .
- What do you want ? - I was called to see Mrs. Warren .
It 's Dr. Parry . Was he called ?
Hello , Helen .
I suppose they called Dr. Harvey first .
You mean Mrs. Warren asked for me ?
Well , I 've got me a patient now .
I 'm glad I was called , Helen . I 've wanted to have a long talk with you
and I 'm going to before I leave .
- How are you , Dr. Parry ? - I 'm fine . How are you , Mrs. Warren ?
Did you know my husband ?
No , I didn 't , Mrs. Warren .
Of course not . He died years before you came here .
You 're a little like him .
Firm step , strong hand
good eyes .
Thank you . I know you were very fond of him .
He told me I wasn 't as beautiful as his first wife
but I was a much better shot .
The only kind of beauty he had any respect for was strength .
And he had two sons
both weaklings .
They hated guns and hunting .
He used to run away from them , Dr. Parry .
Well
he got his release from a bottle .
And he died as he lived , happily , extravagantly .
I 'm sorry .
Oh , no . You mustn 't be .
You mustn 't be sorry for him .
You should try to get some rest , Mrs. Warren .
Yes , I know . I talk too much . I talk too much .
- Get Helen out of this house . - Why ?
Because I know you love her .
Take her away .
Promise me you 'll take her away from here .
Very well , I promise .
Take her away tonight .
If it 's money you need , I 'll get it for you .
Get me the ether , Helen .
Did you get it ?
I 'll go ask Nurse Barker .
Come in , please , nurse .
Will you get me the ether ? Helen can 't find it .
It was used about an hour ago . Where did you put it ?
Let 's have another look .
It 's gone , and you 're the only people who have been in this room today .
- Unless Mrs. Warren- - - You took the ether , Barker .
Why , I did no such thing . You always make me sit outside .
Never mind . Maybe Professor Warren will know about it .
I 'll go and see him .
Here , where 's my brandy ?
I finished it for your own good .
Well , I wish you 'd stop doing things for my own good .
With everything that 's happening , it 's better that you keep your wits .
I 'm never more witty than when I 've had a little nip .
I see better , I hear better , and I feel much better .
Oates , would you mind coming out a moment ? Bring your hat and coat .
There it is .
Emma , let 's be serious for a minute .
I want you to stay awake until I get back .
Keep an eye on Helen . I won 't be long .
I could keep a much better eye on Helen if I 'd had a little nip .
I can 't understand .
Ether was used less than two hours ago .
Stephen used it . He said Helen gave it to him .
Unfortunately , I have no other supply .
Oates , I 'm afraid you 'll have to go into the village for some ether .
It 's stormy out . Does it have to be done ?
If it didn 't have to be done , I wouldn 't ask .
All right , all right , I 'll go .
He won 't find any in the village . I tried to get some .
I have to go to Morristown . It 'll take hours .
I 'm sorry , it 's an emergency . We have to have it .
You 're sorry , but I have to go .
You should have some other stimulant at hand .
- Brandy ? I 'll get a bottle . - That will do .
- Will you ask Helen to come for it ? - Yeah .
Mrs. Oates .
Yes , sir ?
Come along with me while I get a bottle of brandy .
Yes , sir .
Oh , dear , now I 've done it .
- Did you bring a match ? - No , sir .
Oh , well , never mind . Perhaps I have one .
Here we are .
I think it rolled over there , sir .
I 'll take it this time , Mrs. Oates .
Your key , sir .
Oh , my .
Did I put one over on him .
Easy as taking candy from a baby . Take a tip from me , Helen .
If you carry the candle to the cellar for the professor
and you fancy a bottle of his fine old brandy
just throw the candle to one side . Accidentally on purpose , of course .
Anything can happen in the dark .
Presto .
Now , I 'll just wipe this off
and you can take it to Dr. Parry .
Helen .
Come into the den . I want to talk to you .
Mrs. Warren 's asleep .
Professor Warren 's with her now .
I 've been thinking things over . And Mrs. Warren 's right .
You should come with me tonight . You can stay at my mother 's place
until we can make arrangements to go to Boston .
My mother will like you .
I don 't wanna frighten you , but you heard Mrs. Warren a while ago .
Her mind 's growing steadily worse , and I 'm afraid she may become violent .
She seems obsessed by the idea that you get out of this house .
And there may be something back of it .
You 'll go with me tonight .
There are doctors in Boston who 'll know all about your case .
I want to take you there .
Helen .
When I left you this afternoon , I dropped in at the Fabers ' .
They have a guest visiting them from your hometown .
A Mrs. Lindstrom .
You know her ?
Well
she told me a story about a girl .
A girl who was on her way home from school one day .
She had good news for her parents .
When she wasn 't far from her home
she heard a fire engine rushing down the street .
She started to run , and when she turned the corner
she saw that it was her home that was in flames .
There was a crowd outside .
She wanted to scream herself , but somehow she couldn 't .
She tried to rush into the house
but was held back because it was hopeless .
So without being able to do one thing to help
she saw her mother and father burn to death .
I 'm sorry , Helen , but I had to do it .
It 's only because I wanted to help you .
Go over everything that happened that day .
Have the courage to see it all again .
And by not blocking it out of your mind , you may find your voice again .
I don 't like being an outsider , and you shouldn 't either .
I know what I 'm talking about because I 'm an outsider here myself .
A lot of people don 't want me . They want me to quit .
But I won 't , because there 's at least one person who wants me here
and that 's good enough for me .
And there 's one person who wants you to talk
and that ought to be good enough for you . Look at me .
Look at me .
Remember how wonderful it was when you had a voice ?
When you could say " hello " or " thank you " ?
When you could yell back at someone picking at you ?
I do it all the time .
You look at me as though you don 't believe it , but I know I 'm right .
Try to talk ! Try it ! Try it !
Excuse me .
My mother is asking for you , Helen .
I 'll speak to Professor Warren about your leaving .
What is this about Helen leaving ?
I 'll discuss it with your brother .
Is it something you can 't discuss with me ?
Why is she leaving ? Where is she going ?
Well , I 've been doing a great deal of thinking about Helen .
I know her condition is due to shock .
I 'm sure a new mental therapy can restore her voice .
I 'd like to take her to Boston .
Aren 't you taking a tremendous responsibility ?
Building up her hopes .
Making her think there 's some miracle in store for her .
It 's up to her , not you .
What you 're doing is cruel and foolish .
That girl is adjusted to her affliction . I think you should let it go at that .
Suppose you let me mind my own business .
It so happens I don 't think much of your business , Dr. Parry .
If there is a solution to her problem
it ought to be in the hands of someone other than a hick doctor .
The thing that keeps me from cracking you in the jaw
is the almost certain possibility that it would break your neck .
What 's the trouble , doctor ?
The good country doctor , having lost his wits
was about to resort to his fists .
Professor Warren , I know you 're interested in Helen 's welfare .
I 've told you what I 've learned . I 've decided it 's for her best interest ...
- ... that she leave here tonight . - Tonight ?
She can stay at my mother 's until we can take her to Boston
for the examination first thing in the morning .
Doctor , you know that I agree with you
about the element of hope that you have for Helen
but what 's your reason for suddenly making her leave tonight ?
Well , Mrs. Warren feels
that she 's in danger here .
Surely you don 't take the ramblings of a sick woman seriously .
I take most things seriously .
But , doctor , there are many other considerations .
Helen needs this position . It 's her only means of support .
No family . It won 't be easy- -
I 've thought of all those things , professor .
I ... .
I intend to take care of her .
Oh , I see .
Well , I 'm very glad for you and for her .
You 're a sentimentalist , doctor .
Are your humanitarian instincts restricted
only to people with serious afflictions ?
You 're very insolent .
Dr. Parry .
Excuse me .
Hello ?
Yes , he is . Just a moment .
- It 's for you , doctor . - Thank you .
Hello ?
Helen
the Wilson boy is sick . I have to go over there .
Now , here 's their phone number . You can pack while I 'm gone .
If you need anything before I get back , have Mrs. Oates call me .
I 'll be back as soon as I can .
Be sure and bar the door behind me .
And don 't let anyone in but me .
Wilt thou obey him
serve him
Iove , honor and keep him , in sickness and in health
and forsaking all others
keep thee only unto him
so long as ye both shall live ?
Signify by saying , " I do . "
Say , " I do . "
What 's the matter , Helen ? Don 't you feel well ?
I understand you 're going to leave us .
Well , I don 't know whether Dr. Parry is right or wrong
but I agree that you should have that chance to go to Boston .
And I want you to understand if things don 't work out satisfactorily
that you 're always welcome to come here .
Now , you run along .
I like to see women cry .
Men like to see women cry . It makes them feel superior .
Oh , Steve
I 'm very unhappy
and upset .
You dramatize everything , Blanche .
We 've been very happy . At least , I have .
- I don 't like your attitude at all . - I 'm sorry .
It 's just , I 'm- - I 'm making trouble between you and your stepbrother .
I don 't like to hide anything I feel .
And you know how I feel about you .
That 's very sweet of you , Blanche .
But are you sure you 're telling me the truth ?
Truth about what ?
Just that I think you 're uncomfortable because of your
past relationship with my brother .
- You are a- - - Don 't say it .
Just answer my question .
Get out .
Don 't be so melodramatic .
I didn 't realize you were so strong .
I 'm leaving here .
I never want to see you again .
I 'll miss you .
A house like this needs charm .
I told you to get out .
You 're going to regret this .
I 'm sorry to intrude , Helen .
I have a favor to ask of you .
You 're leaving tonight , and I want to go into town with you .
I 'm happy for you .
Things will be so different when you 're cured .
I don 't know what will become of me , but I 've got to leave this house .
It hasn 't been good for anyone here .
I 'm only taking a few things with me .
Oates can pick up my other things tomorrow .
My suitcase is in the basement . I 'll only be a few minutes .
This is the second time I 've closed that window tonight .
I definitely know I did .
Now , if only I knew who opened it .
You 're not that clever , and if you were ... .
Oh , it 's you . You scared the life out of me .
I told you not to touch me . Get out .
I 'll get out , Mrs. Warren . Not only out of here ...
- ... but out of this house . - Good riddance .
But before I go , you 're going to hear a few things .
I 'm tired of being a target for an evil old woman .
Nobody 's asking you to stay .
If you got down on your knees , I wouldn 't stay .
- I don 't need this job . - Why don 't you go ?
You need a keeper , not a nurse . I don 't care if you never walk again .
You can stay in that bed for the rest of your life .
I 've taken everything , but I 'll not put up with this .
I 'm leaving this house tonight .
I 'll soon clear them out .
I hate nurses . Always fussing .
Always washing your face .
Helen .
Did you know there was a girl murdered here a long time ago ?
I saw it .
Upstairs , from the window .
It was getting dark .
I thought it was a tree in the garden .
Stood so still
and waited .
Then when the poor , simple-minded creature came near the house
the tree moved
threw her into the well .
I was too late .
I couldn 't find the rope .
You were that girl , Helen .
Come here .
You must go away .
Leave this house .
Go with Nurse Barker tonight .
Don 't wait for Dr. Parry . Don 't wait for anyone .
If you won 't , you must do what I tell you .
You must get under the bed .
Do you understand ?
You must hide under the bed .
Why won 't you do what I tell you to ?
Why won 't you listen to me ?
Why won 't anyone listen to me ?
Would you mind letting me have a wagon ?
I 'll leave it in the village for Oates to pick up .
Very well . I 'll go out with you and hitch up the wagon .
You 're very kind , professor .
I 've been walking .
- In this rain ? - Yes .
In this rain .
I wonder if you 'd mind doing something for me , Stephen .
What ?
Nurse Barker is leaving us .
And as long as you 're already rather wet
perhaps you wouldn 't mind hitching up the wagon for her .
Everybody 's leaving the old homestead .
Like a holiday .
- It 'll be a pleasure . - For both of us .
- Goodbye , Professor Warren . - Goodbye .
Oh , Helen , will you tell Blanche I want to see her in the den ?
Have you been here long ?
I was outside with Nurse Barker . I saw the basement door open .
Did you come in that way ?
Helen
you must forget everything you 've seen here .
Let me handle this . Do you understand ?
Take the candle .
Come with me .
You don 't think I did it .
Wait .
I think I have a match . Yes .
Where could it go ?
Hey , there it is .
Helen !
Let me out of here !
Number , please .
Hello .
Hello . Number , please .
Helen .
What on earth are you doing ? What 's the matter ?
" Blanche murdered " ?
" Stephen . "
Where ?
I 'll take you up to my stepmother 's room .
You stay there with her .
I 'll call the constable .
Let me take care of things now .
You 've been through enough .
You tried to telephone , didn 't you ?
Well , I 'm glad you couldn 't .
You looked in this mirror once before today .
I watched you .
You had no mouth then .
Just as you have none now .
Look at yourself .
Look .
And there 's no room in the whole world
for imperfection .
The only person who could have prevented you
from achieving the quiet that I can give you
was Stephen .
And you locked him up
downstairs .
We 're quiet now , Helen .
I 'm glad I waited .
Everyone 's out of the way .
Mrs. Oates is drunk
because I purposely let her steal a bottle of brandy .
And Oates
he 's gone to look for ether
because I made sure there was no ether .
And Blanche
whom I loved
didn 't love me
so she had to die .
She 's dead and at peace .
And Stephen
you took care of him for me .
Stephen is weak
as I once was .
What a pity my father didn 't live to see me become strong .
To see me dispose of the weak and imperfects
of the world , whom he detested .
He would have admired me for what I 'm going to do .
- Who is it ? - It 's me , the constable .
I met Dr. Parry in town .
He said he won 't be able to pick Helen up tonight .
The boy is very sick , and he has to stay there .
Oh , I 'm sorry to hear that . I 'll tell her , constable .
Well , I 'll be on my way then . Good night .
Helen !
Murderer .
You killed them .
You killed them all .
The servant girl in the well .
The others in the town .
Today , the cripple in the hotel .
You killed them all .
Tonight , it would have been Helen .
I heard you .
Stephen .
Get me Stephen .
Now it 's been done .
Ten years too late .
No .
Forgive me , Stephen .
I thought it was you .
He always waited till you came home
so I thought it was you .
A doctor . Get Dr. Parry . Hurry !
One
eight
nine .
Dr. Parry .
Come .
It 's I , Helen .